<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TomorrowScale</title>
    <description>Stories from the cutting edge of science and medicine.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 09:28:16 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 09:28:16 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>On-Demand Biology - Tierra Biosciences</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/embed/episodes/On-Demand-Biology---Tierra-Biosciences-efv774&quot; height=&quot;102px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you build biology? Simple: DNA to RNA to proteins, right? Not so fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each one of your trillions of cells are themselves little factories, constantly producing various peptides and proteins that your body needs from building blocks of amino acids encoded by our genes. Multiple industries use various forms of biological manufacturing wherein they’ve harnessed cells of some kind: yeast, E coli, animal, and human cell lines to manufacture proteins for us. But there are downsides to traditional cell culture methods; those same cells that protect also constrain. And some scientists want to leave the cell behind entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this episode, we’ll speak about the potential of cell-free manufacturing “bits to biology” with Tierra Biosciences CEO Zachary Sun, PhD, who co-founded Tierra with leading synthetic biologists in Harvard’s George Church and CalTech’s Richard Murray. Their vision is to “break free of the cell and fundamentally change how scientists approach discovery.” Launched just last month, Sol by Tierra is a cell-free manufacturing system that serves as a biological synthesis-as-a-service layer for R&amp;amp;D scientists. And it could play a key role enabling an on-demand biological future, where the protein of interest is just a click away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the TomorrowScale Podcast. Hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/briggsly&quot;&gt;Justin Briggs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tierra Biosciences:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://tierrabiosciences.com&quot;&gt;https://tierrabiosciences.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sol by Tierra:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow us on Twitter:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/tomorrowscale&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener ugc noreferrer&quot;&gt;http://twitter.com/tomorrowscale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen on &lt;a href=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/&quot;&gt;Your Favorite Podcast App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TomorrowScale Podcast was created to showcase scientists and entrepreneurs who are building science-based businesses, and to hear stories from the benches and in the trenches of research &amp;amp; development. The views expressed by the host and guests are their own, and the content of this show should not be considered legal, tax, or investing advice. Thanks to our guests for sharing their time and knowledge with us. Thank you for listening. Please science responsibly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/on-demand-biology-tierra-biosciences</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/on-demand-biology-tierra-biosciences</guid>
        
        
        <category>biology</category>
        
        <category>chemistry</category>
        
        <category>engineering</category>
        
        <category>manufacturing</category>
        
        <category>synthetic biology</category>
        
        <category>genetics</category>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nature's Nuclear - Oklo, Inc.</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/embed/episodes/Natures-Nuclear---Oklo-Inc-efad3j&quot; height=&quot;102px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this episode Oklo co-founders Jacob DeWitte and Caroline Cochran join us to discuss what it took to get their startup to this point in development of the first advanced nuclear fission power plant; how a chance meeting with Sam Altman (OpenAI, YCombinator) changed their path; and how to think big, by starting small, even in nuclear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year Oklo became the first company to submit a combined construction and operating license application to the United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission (or NRC) for what is called an “advanced fission power plant.” Their design, the Aurora “powerhouse” centers around the concept not of a traditional reactor, but of a small, modular fission battery hundreds of times smaller than traditional reactors. Listen as Jake and Caroline take us through the fascinating founding story of Oklo and their big vision for the small future of clean energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the TomorrowScale Podcast. Hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/briggsly&quot;&gt;Justin Briggs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oklo Inc: &lt;a href=&quot;https://oklo.com/&quot;&gt;https://oklo.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aurora Powerhouse Press Release: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20191202005499/en/Oklo-Announces-Aurora-Advanced-Fission-Clean-Energy&quot;&gt;via https://businesswire.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aurora’s NRC Application Accepted for Docketing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ans.org/news/article-269/auroras-docketing-marks-dawn-for-advanced-reactor-licensing/&quot;&gt;via American Nuclear Solciety&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow us on Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/tomorrowscale&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener ugc noreferrer&quot;&gt;http://twitter.com/tomorrowscale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen on &lt;a href=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/&quot;&gt;Your Favorite Podcast App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TomorrowScale Podcast was created to showcase scientists and entrepreneurs who are building science-based businesses, and to hear their stories from the benches and in the trenches of research &amp;amp; development. The views expressed by the host and guests are their own, and the content of this show should not be considered legal, tax, or investing advice. Thanks to our guests for sharing their time and knowledge with us. Thank you for listening. Please science responsibly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/natures-nuclear-oklo-inc</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/natures-nuclear-oklo-inc</guid>
        
        
        <category>physics</category>
        
        <category>nuclear</category>
        
        <category>engineering</category>
        
        <category>chemistry</category>
        
        <category>energy</category>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trials to Your Door - Sanguine Biosciences</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/embed/episodes/Trials-to-Your-Door---Sanguine-Biosciences-eenbh9&quot; height=&quot;102px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the center of every clinical trial is a group of patients; each with a medical condition that we seek to understand more about through interacting with those patients directly. Startups like Sanguine Biosciences are part of a clinical services innovation layer, connecting population health, clinical research, and healthcare delivery in new ways using new technologies. On this episode, our guest is Brian Neman, CEO of Sanguine Biosciences, and adjunct instructor at the University of Southern California’s Price School of Public Policy. We discuss how recent technological advancements enable new way to make clinical research more patient-centric, better efficiency, and—critically in the time of COVID-19, ensure continuity of care and the advancement of medical research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the TomorrowScale Podcast. Hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/briggsly&quot;&gt;Justin Briggs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sanguine Biosciences:&lt;/strong&gt; https://sanguinebio.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen on &lt;a href=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/&quot;&gt;Your Favorite Podcast App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclosures: The host and guest have no conflicts to disclose. Mr. Briggs and companies he is affiliated with are not current or previous clients of Sanguine Biosciences.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TomorrowScale Podcast was created to showcase scientists and entrepreneurs who are building science-based businesses, and to hear their stories from the benches and in the trenches of research &amp;amp; development. The views expressed by the host and guests are their own, and the content of this show should not be considered legal, tax, or investing advice. Thanks to our guests for sharing their time and knowledge with us. Thank you for listening. Please science responsibly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/trials-to-your-door-sanguine-biosciences</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/trials-to-your-door-sanguine-biosciences</guid>
        
        
        <category>medicine</category>
        
        <category>biology</category>
        
        <category>biotech</category>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Your Digital Twin - UnlearnAI</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/embed/episodes/Your-Digital-Twin---UnlearnAI-ee0le3&quot; height=&quot;102px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this episode we’ll meet biophysicist, machine learning researcher, and CEO of UnlearnAI Dr. Charles Fisher. He and the team at Unlearn have the goal to build the entire biomedical machine learning stack, from scratch. Their strategy is that with a fit-for-purpose biomedical machine learning infrastructure and novel deep learning techniques, along with enough data about patients, that they can generate synthetic versions of actual patients, entirely in the data, with the goal to make them “computationally indistinguishable” from real patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A “digital twin” could help to better understand the impact of medicines before they’re used in a real patient, or in clinical trials to be used alongside real patients in what they call “intelligent control arms.” Unlearn believes that we can obtain the same rigorous, statistically-powered clinical evidence but with fewer subjects. A fascinating approach to the problem of how to make clinical trials more efficient, and understand more about what may be possible with more and better patient data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the TomorrowScale Podcast. Hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/briggsly&quot;&gt;Justin Briggs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unlearn AI:&lt;/strong&gt; https://unlearn.health&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charles Fisher CV, Google Scholar:&lt;/strong&gt; https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=MQlhMlwAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boltzmann Encoded Adversarial Machines (BEAM) paper:&lt;/strong&gt; https://arxiv.org/pdf/1804.08682.pdf&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“The FDA needs to set standards for using artificial intelligence in drug development” by Dr. Charles Fisher in StatNews, 11/7/2019:&lt;/strong&gt; https://www.statnews.com/2019/11/07/artificial-intelligence-drug-development-fda-standards-needed/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Fisher’s presentation at a recent FDA Meeting (begins on page 175; linked here since we didn’t end up discussing each point after all):&lt;/strong&gt; https://www.fda.gov/media/136577/download#page=175&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photocredit: Dr. Fisher’s headshot, augmented based on the blue binary background image, using a neural style transfer model found here:&lt;/strong&gt; https://git.io/Jf4a6&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen on &lt;a href=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/&quot;&gt;Your Favorite Podcast App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TomorrowScale Podcast was created to showcase scientists and entrepreneurs who are building science-based businesses, and to hear their stories from the benches and in the trenches of research &amp;amp; development. The views expressed by the host and guests are their own, and the content of this show should not be considered legal, tax, or investing advice. Thanks to our guests for sharing their time and knowledge with us. Thank you for listening. Please science responsibly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/your-digital-twin-unlearnai</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/your-digital-twin-unlearnai</guid>
        
        
        <category>medicine</category>
        
        <category>biology</category>
        
        <category>machine learning</category>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>biotech</category>
        
        <category>data science</category>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Measure of Medicine - Prof Frank Lichtenberg</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/embed/episodes/Proof-of-Prophylaxis---MIT-Langer-Lab---Drs--Ana-Jaklenec--Kevin-McHugh-e9vbp1&quot; height=&quot;102px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this show we talk a lot about the opportunity and the promise of innovation. It is incredibly difficult, however, to study the actual impact of those new technologies. In healthcare, we do have some chance to measure the impact of new medicines. But! What data do we use? What metrics are used? and why are they used? Today’s guest is Dr. Frank Lichtenberg, the Courtney C. Brown Professor of Business at the Graduate School of Business at Columbia University. Dr. Lichtenberg has taught at Columbia, Harvard, and Penn, worked for the Department of Justice, the Congressional Budget Office, and the Census Bureau, and has conducted several large studies on the impact of pharmaceutical innovation across diseases and geographies over the last 25 years. Right now, billions are sheltering in place from a pathogen that we must fight with drugs and vaccines. The purpose of this conversation is to gain a little bit better understanding of an important topic, relayed in the voice of a leading researcher, so that we may, in the future, invent and develop safer, better technologies to fight disease. To do that, we must measure medicine’s impact not only on the patient, but also the patient population, the healthcare system, and the entire economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the TomorrowScale Podcast. Hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/briggsly&quot;&gt;Justin Briggs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Lichtenberg’s Columbia Page:&lt;/strong&gt; https://www8.gsb.columbia.edu/cbs-directory/detail/frl1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Lichtenberg’s Publications via Google Scholar:&lt;/strong&gt; https://scholar.google.com/citations?hl=en&amp;amp;user=t3NSVwoAAAAJ&amp;amp;view_op=list_works&amp;amp;sortby=pubdate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen on &lt;a href=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/&quot;&gt;Your Favorite Podcast App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TomorrowScale Podcast was created to showcase scientists and entrepreneurs who are building science-based businesses, and to hear their stories from the benches and in the trenches of research &amp;amp; development. The views expressed by the host and guests are their own, and the content of this show should not be considered legal, tax, or investing advice. Thanks to our guests for sharing their time and knowledge with us. Thank you for listening. Please science responsibly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-measure-of-medicine-prof-lichtenberg</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-measure-of-medicine-prof-lichtenberg</guid>
        
        
        <category>medicine</category>
        
        <category>economics</category>
        
        <category>biotech</category>
        
        <category>research</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Computing the Universe - Jonathan Gorard, Wolfram Physics Project</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/embed/episodes/Computing-the-Universe---Jonathan-Gorard--Wolfram-Physics-edcssn&quot; height=&quot;102px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this episode, we’ll speak with one of the principal researchers on the Wolfram Physics Project, Jonathan Gorard. We’ll discuss how they plan to actually implement their “fundamental theory of the universe” and build these computational universes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Gorard is a theoretical mathematician, researcher at the University of Cambridge, and consultant to Wolfram Research. He is ostensibly the scientist tasked with doing the maths to demonstrate these concepts to the scientific community and the public. Actually proving these ideas out in the open, over the din of more than a few detractors, may be one of the most difficult parts of this highly complex project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with a call for scientists everywhere to contribute and critique the project in an open-source manner, the team published nearly a thousand pages and over 500 hours of video. All since Wolfram’s announcement on April 14th titled, “We may have found a fundamental theory of the universe… and it’s beautiful.” The Wolfram Physics team, consisting of Stephen Wolfram, Jonathan Gorard, and theoretical physicist and competitive programmer Max Piskanov, are literally live-streaming the entire thing. Scientific discovery, open collaboration, and peer review happening in real-time, and anyone can get involved. Now that is beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the TomorrowScale Podcast. Hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/briggsly&quot;&gt;Justin Briggs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wolfram Physics Project Website:&lt;/strong&gt; https://www.wolframphysics.org/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Announcement by Stephen Wolfram:&lt;/strong&gt; https://writings.stephenwolfram.com/2020/04/finally-we-may-have-a-path-to-the-fundamental-theory-of-physics-and-its-beautiful/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Registry of Notable Universes:&lt;/strong&gt; https://www.wolframphysics.org/universes/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jonathan Gorard, Cambridge University Center for Scientific Computing:&lt;/strong&gt; https://www.csc.cam.ac.uk/academic/MPhilSciComp/directory/gorard&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen on &lt;a href=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/&quot;&gt;Your Favorite Podcast App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TomorrowScale Podcast was created to showcase scientists and entrepreneurs who are building science-based businesses, and to hear their stories from the benches and in the trenches of research &amp;amp; development. The views expressed by the host and guests are their own, and the content of this show should not be considered legal, tax, or investing advice. Thanks to our guests for sharing their time and knowledge with us. Thank you for listening. Please science responsibly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/computing-the-universe-jonathan-gorard</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/computing-the-universe-jonathan-gorard</guid>
        
        
        <category>mathematics</category>
        
        <category>physics</category>
        
        <category>machine learning</category>
        
        <category>data science</category>
        
        <category>research</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Accelerating Evolution - Prof Chang Liu</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/embed/episodes/Accelerating-Evolution---Prof--Chang-Liu-ecrin1&quot; height=&quot;102px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Chang Liu, assistant professor of biomedical engineering at the University of California, Irvine, has transformed traditional yeast culture methods into an engine to accelerate evolution in order to understand the drivers of selection and gain the ability view fitness not as a crossroads, but a landscape–a mutational topology that he and his collaborators are able to navigate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ACE, or automated continuous evolution, combines the Liu Lab’s orthogonal replication system, OrthoRep, with the robotic culturing system eVOVLR, developed by the Khalil Lab at Boston University, to automate evolution. Together, they can synthesize new biology; build novel enzymes and proteins to serve multiple industries; and, even help us fight not just today’s pandemic but tomorrow’s pandemics as well. A story of discovery in the fast-paced world of synthetic biology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the TomorrowScale Podcast. Hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/briggsly&quot;&gt;Justin Briggs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ACE pre-print on bioRxiv:&lt;/strong&gt; https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.02.21.960328&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liu Lab at UC Irvine:&lt;/strong&gt; https://liulab.com/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Khalil Lab at BU:&lt;/strong&gt; https://www.bu.edu/khalillab/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen on &lt;a href=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/&quot;&gt;Your Favorite Podcast App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TomorrowScale Podcast was created to showcase scientists and entrepreneurs who are building science-based businesses, and to hear their stories from the benches and in the trenches of research &amp;amp; development. The views expressed by the host and guests are their own, and the content of this show should not be considered legal, tax, or investing advice. Thanks to our guests for sharing their time and knowledge with us. Thank you for listening. Please science responsibly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/accelerating-evolution-prof-chang-liu</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/accelerating-evolution-prof-chang-liu</guid>
        
        
        <category>chemistry</category>
        
        <category>biology</category>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>biotech</category>
        
        <category>podcast</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chemification - Prof Lee Cronin</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/embed/episodes/Chemification---Prof--Lee-Cronin-ecajia&quot; height=&quot;102px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, there was chemistry. Well, not exactly. From those primordial reaction conditions … life emerged. But how? What separates chemistry from biology? How do we study the origin of life? What can we do with a Chemputer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this episode, we’ll head to the lab of Dr. Lee Cronin, Regius Professor of Chemistry at the University of Glasgow, Scotland, and perhaps one of the most provocative chemists in the field today. We’ll discuss his lab’s view into the origin of life, the balance between theory and reality, and how the Chemputer could be an important component to the future of chemistry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the TomorrowScale Podcast. Hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/briggsly&quot;&gt;Justin Briggs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cronin Lab:&lt;/strong&gt; https://croninlab.com
&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Cronin on Twitter:&lt;/strong&gt; https://twitter.com/leecronin
&lt;strong&gt;Chemify.org:&lt;/strong&gt; http://chemify.org&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen on &lt;a href=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/&quot;&gt;Your Favorite Podcast App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TomorrowScale Podcast was created to showcase scientists and entrepreneurs who are building science-based businesses, and to hear their stories from the benches and in the trenches of research &amp;amp; development. The views expressed by the host and guests are their own, and the content of this show should not be considered legal, tax, or investing advice. Thanks to our guests for sharing their time and knowledge with us. Thank you for listening. Please science responsibly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/chemification-prof-lee-cronin</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/chemification-prof-lee-cronin</guid>
        
        
        <category>chemistry</category>
        
        <category>biology</category>
        
        <category>machine learning</category>
        
        <category>robotics</category>
        
        <category>biotech</category>
        
        <category>research</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building a Brain - Rain Neuromorphics</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/embed/episodes/Building-a-Brain---Rain-Neuromorphics-ebut4s&quot; height=&quot;102px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does the future of scientific computing look like? Labs all over the world are racing to build chips based on our brains. But what can it do? And what will it be used for? On this episode, we’ll meet a company that built an actual analog neural network in order to solve this problem. Gordon Wilson, CEO of Rain Neuromorphics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the TomorrowScale Podcast. Hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/briggsly&quot;&gt;Justin Briggs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rain Neuromorphics:&lt;/strong&gt; https://rain.ai&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen on &lt;a href=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/&quot;&gt;Your Favorite Podcast App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TomorrowScale Podcast was created to showcase scientists and entrepreneurs who are building science-based businesses, and to hear their stories from the benches and in the trenches of research &amp;amp; development. The views expressed by the host and guests are their own, and the content of this show should not be considered legal, tax, or investing advice. Thanks to our guests for sharing their time and knowledge with us. Thank you for listening. Please science responsibly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/building-a-brain-rain-neuromorphics</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/building-a-brain-rain-neuromorphics</guid>
        
        
        <category>biology</category>
        
        <category>vaccines</category>
        
        <category>materials</category>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>biotech</category>
        
        <category>podcast</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Engineering the (Immune) System - DistributedBio</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/embed/episodes/Engineering-the-Immune-System---DistributedBio-ebie91&quot; height=&quot;102px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this episode we sit down with star scientists from Netflix’s show ‘Pandemic,’ DistributedBio co-founder and CEO Jacob Glanville, and Centivax program lead and director of contract research Sarah Ives. We’ll hear more about the company’s founding story, get perspective on bootstrapping a biotech company, and learn more about their internal and client development programs that cover everything from vaccines, antibodies, and chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T cell therapies, and which target diseases as varied as influenza, HIV, cancer, and even the SARS-CoV2 Coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the TomorrowScale Podcast. Hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/briggsly&quot;&gt;Justin Briggs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DistributedBio:&lt;/strong&gt; https://distributedbio.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Centivax:&lt;/strong&gt; https://www.centivax.com/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow us on Twitter:&lt;/strong&gt; https://twitter.com/tomorrowscale&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen on &lt;a href=&quot;https://anchor.fm/tomorrowscale/&quot;&gt;Your Favorite Podcast App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TomorrowScale Podcast was created to showcase scientists and entrepreneurs who are building science-based businesses, and to hear their stories from the benches and in the trenches of research &amp;amp; development. The views expressed by the host and guests are their own, and the content of this show should not be considered legal, tax, or investing advice. Thanks to our guests for sharing their time and knowledge with us. Thank you for listening. Please science responsibly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/engineering-the-immune-system-distributedbio</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/engineering-the-immune-system-distributedbio</guid>
        
        
        <category>biology</category>
        
        <category>engineering</category>
        
        <category>vaccines</category>
        
        <category>drug discovery</category>
        
        <category>biotech</category>
        
        <category>startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
